Muhammad Naveed Iftikhar, PhD

Email: naveed@atomcamp.com Cell: +92-334-4224998

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am co-founder of atomcamp & Polix Analytics Ltd (UK). atomcamp is a Data Science and Al training company, and Polix Analytics Ltd. provides Data Science and Al solutions. I have been performing business leadership roles to deliver data and Al solutions to national and international companies, governments and cities. I have delivered several executive trainings and taught at renowned business schools in Pakistan like IBA Karachi, KSBL and SDSB, LUMS. I have also developed data based policies and solutions for federal and provincial governments in Pakistan as a technical expert with the World Bank, Asian Development Bank and UNDP.

EMPLOYMENT RECORD

Atomcamp- Since 2020

Co-founder

- Overseeing Data Science and Al training to the workforce nationally and internationally
- Delivered tech trainings to ARAMCO, Tamimi Group KSA, King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals, Government of Azerbaijan, NUST, USIP, UNICEF, UNODC, and Planning Commission.
- Leading in providing Al solutions to local clients like the Legal Aid Society, UNoDC, and CITY at LUMS.
- Deploying Al solutions within team like automation, chatbot, and data strategy.
- Led the project of Social Media Sentiment Analysis in Pakistan.

Polix Analytics

Co-founder- Since 2023

Providing AI solutions in KSA and USA:

- Computer Vision-based quality inspection of a construction company
- Warehousing & Inventory Management of a manufacturing company
- Al-powered Quality Control Solution for a rebar manufacturing comany
- Comprehensive Data Analytics Solution for a rental equipment services company
- Al-powered Customer Interaction & Pricing Strategy Solution for a rental equipment services company
- Mobile App for Crime Reporting & Analysis
- Al strategies for companies and governments.

Lahore University of Management Sciences (LUMS), CITY at LUMS

Research Advisor/- June 2023- Dec 2024

Advising on the application of data science and AI in city management.

Lahore University of Management Sciences (LUMS), Suleman Dawood School of Business

Adjunct Faculty/- Oct 2019-Dec 2022

 Taught courses on urban planning and management in Fall 2019 and facilitated improvement in the design, relevance and quality of MS (Business & Public Policy), a new graduate program launched by Suleman Dawood School of Business. Developed and taught a new course on Policy Analysis and Communication for the MS (Business & Public Policy).

University of Delaware-USA, School of Public Policy and Administration Research Fellow/- Sep 2015-June 2017

• Research on technology entrepreneurship, governance, public policy, urbanization, public administration, and performance budgeting.

Ministry of Finance, Government of Pakistan-Economic Reforms Unit (ERU) Governance Specialist- Dec 2007 to May 2014

- Coordinated a team of professionals for formulation and implementation of institutional reforms, social policy and public-sector management improvement initiatives.
- Worked with budgetary data sets, power sector data and SOEs data set identifying trends for a data-driven policy making.

ConsTech Management and Development Consultants, Lahore-Pakistan Manager Projects-January 2004 to Dec 2007

 Managed consulting and training services for reputable public, private, civil society, and international organizations in the areas of organizational development, quality assurance, monitoring & evaluation and performance management.

VISITING FACULTY

Taught economics and public policy courses at universities and civil service training institutions including Lahore University of Management Sciences (LUMS), Institute of Business Administration (IBA) Karachi, Pakistan Institute of Development Economics (PIDE), National Defense University (NDU), Quaid-i-Azam University, National Institute of Management Islamabad, Peshawar and Lahore, and Karachi School of Business and Leadership.

EDUCATION

PhD (Public Policy) University of Delaware, USA 2019
Dissertation: Technology Entrepreneurship, Knowledge Spillover, and Urbanization in Asia